(competition in life)
（較量人生）
(The characters, events, groups, organizations and backgrounds of this drama are purely fictitious. We hereby inform you that)
（本劇之人物、事件、團體、組織 及背景等，純屬虛構，特此告知）
(Episode 11)
（第11集）
Let's get started
那就開始吧
About PR Team 2 Agent Yoo Jae-min
關於公關二組柳才旻代理
Acted by Park Yun-soo of PR Team 3
與公關三組朴允昭代理的
The Personnel Committee will now be held
人事委員會現在開始舉行
before that
在那之前
There are other people who are going to be there in person
還有其他人要親臨現場
who is it?
是誰啊？
Why is Director Goo here?
具理事怎麼會來這裡？
Director Goo, would you please preside over it?
具理事，麻煩你主持了
How is this going?
這是怎麼回事？
(One week before the Personnel Committee is held)
（召開人事委員會一週前）
(Se Yong)
（世容）
Please come in
請進
(General Manager of Sales Department)
（營業本部長）
Please cancel the convening of the personnel committee
請你取消召開人事委員會
Then I'm afraid I can't do it
那我恐怕辦不到
Do you really have no idea what the real problem is?
你真的不知道什麼才是 真正的問題嗎？
The PR office should not be blamed for this matter!
這件事不該讓公關室背黑鍋！
No, the PR office must take full responsibility for this
不對，公關室得為此負起全責
And not just them, but you too
而且不光是他們，還包括你
The company is not a charity
公司又不是什麼慈善機構
How long will I tolerate you?
到底要容忍你到何時啊？
Why should we suffer the consequences of your incompetence?
我們為什麼要承受 你的無能所導致的後果？
Not to mention not just once, but twice!
何況又不止一次，是兩次！
If nothing can be done to remedy this situation, Shi Yonghui will collapse.
萬一這次無法補救得當 世容會就此倒下的
I want to prevent that from happening
我是想阻止那種事發生
And that's it for you!
而你就到此為止了！
Is the personnel committee going to be convened so soon?
這麼快就要召開人事委員會？
And the target is not the sales manager but an employee of the public relations office?
而且對象還不是營業負責人 而是公關室員工？
Doesn’t that mean the company wants to push us to take bullets?
那不就表示公司 要推我們出去擋子彈嗎？
Seeing them do all the dirty things makes people more convinced that there must be something evil.
看他們做盡了骯髒事 反而讓人更加確信一定有鬼
What on earth were they trying to cover up to get to this point?
他們究竟是想掩蓋什麼 才做到這種地步？
Hello
喂
When did Team Leader Song get involved and how did he get involved?
宋組長是從何時開始涉入 又是怎麼扯上關係的？
I asked him
我有問過他
- But he avoided the question - would he openly admit it?
-但他迴避了這個問題 -難道他會大方承認嗎？
How could any fool go and ask him face to face?
怎麼會有傻子跑去當面問他呢？
And you are the fool
而你就是那個傻子
Damn it, you scared me
可惡，嚇我一跳
You said you want to hold an emergency countermeasures meeting?
你說要開緊急對策會議？
No matter what the name of this meeting is,
姑且不論這會議的名稱叫什麼
But the current situation is indeed urgent
但目前的情況確實很緊急
What will happen if a personnel committee is convened?
召開人事委員會的話會發生什麼事？
That's just a necessary process for making punishments
那只是做出懲戒的必經過程
Now there are rumors outside
現在外面在謠傳
If you are punished, it will be Director Goo’s turn next.
要是你們受到懲戒 接下來就輪到具理事了
Why is everyone targeting Director Goo?
為什麼每個人都要針對具理事？
Why is everyone so anxious to remove her?
為什麼大家都急著拉她下臺？
Now that's not the point
現在那又不是重點
But what do you two plan to do?
而是你們兩個打算怎麼做
This forged ingredient analysis list given to Houji by Team Leader Song
宋組長給厚佶的這份 偽造的成分分析表
I think we should start investigating from here
我認為要從這裡著手調查
Scared me
嚇死我了
It's clearly visible from outside
外面看得一清二楚
Why should countermeasures meetings be held in the company?
對策會議為什麼要在公司開？
-There are eyeliners everywhere here -Seunghee
-這裡到處都是眼線 -勝熙
What you plan to do is also our share.
你們打算做的事也算我們一份吧
Seung Hee
勝熙
It seems like I haven’t seen Agent Xu for a long time.
我好像很久沒見到許代理了呢
I also want to help you
我也想助你們一臂之力
I can't put all the blame on you two.
不能把責任都推到你們兩位身上
That's wrong
那樣是不對的
Agent Xu
許代理
I can't tell you are so good at talking
看不出來你這麼會說話
What to do? What to start with?
要做什麼？先從什麼開始？
My problem is no longer within our capabilities
我的問題已經不是 我們能力所及的範圍了
Let’s all help solve Agent Liu’s problem together .
大家還是一起幫忙解決 柳代理的問題吧
Now who leaked that report?
現在那篇報導是誰走漏消息的
It's no longer the point
已經不是重點了
Then go inquire about the sales team.
那麼去打探營業組吧
My connections are no joke
我的人脈可不是鬧著玩的
but
不過
We should also solve the problem of Agent Park, right?
我們也應該一併解決 朴代理的問題吧？
That negative marketing
那個負面行銷
I heard from Jihyo that you were actually firmly opposed to it at the beginning.
我聽智孝說你一開始 其實是堅決反對的
So why should you be punished alone?
那為什麼要由你獨自受罰？
I believe you and like you
我相信你，也喜歡你
Hey, what is this?
喂，這是什麼？
By the way, this is the ingredient analysis table, show it to them.
對了，這是成分分析表 拿給他們看看吧
Well, that is to say
好，也就是說
This is the ingredient analysis list given to Houji by Team Leader Song
這是宋組長給厚佶的成分分析表
right
對
This is the analysis table I commissioned separately.
這是我另外委託的分析表
(Is Shi Yong not related to the death of the boss of a certain outsourcing company ?)
（世容與某家外包廠商老闆之死 毫無關聯嗎？）
Well, this is very well written.
這個嘛，寫得很好啊
But Jae Min…
但才旻…
Huiying
慧瑛
This is not something you should feel guilty about
這不是你該感到愧疚的事
You didn't peek on purpose, you just happened to see it
你又不是故意偷看的 只是碰巧看見了
Didn’t you also tell Cai Min?
你不是也跟才旻說了嗎？
I only said it after I decided to write the report. At most, it was just to inform him.
我是在決定寫成報導後才說的 那充其量只是知會他一聲
If you pretended not to know for Jaemin's sake, would you feel better now?
如果你為才旻著想而假裝不知情 現在心裡就會好過一點嗎？
I don't think so, you must be very anxious
我可不這麼認為，你一定會很焦慮
I guess we don't have to worry about Jae Min
我想我們不必為才旻擔心
I like you
我喜歡你
I said I like you
我說我喜歡你
Come date with me
跟我交往吧
You don’t have a date right now, do you?
你現在沒有交往對象吧？
Have you ever dated a girl?
你有跟女生交往過嗎？
Here we go again, you asked the same question
又來了，你也問了一樣的問題
But does it matter whether you’ve been in a relationship or not?
但有沒有交往過很重要嗎？
important
重要
Very important
非常重要
in Korea
在韓國
This kind of relationship cannot be disclosed easily
是無法輕易公開這種關係的
Suppose someone asks you if you have a date
假設有人問你有沒有交往對象
Then he asked when you plan to get married.
接著又問你打算何時結婚
You can't answer this kind of question at all
你根本回答不了這類問題
Over time, you will start to think about giving up.
久而久之，你就會萌生放棄的念頭
“I want to show off my significant other to others and receive blessings from others
“我想向別人炫耀我的另一半 接受他人的祝福
I also want to have ordinary love in the eyes of others.”
也想擁有別人眼中的平凡愛情”
In the end you will choose to leave
最後你就會選擇離開
Those who think there is no difference
那些認為沒有區別的人
Maybe I haven't thought about this problem at all
也許根本沒思考過這種問題
In short
總之
It's something to be grateful for when someone likes me, so thank you.
有人喜歡我是件值得感激的事 所以謝謝你
It seems…
看來…
You are quite extreme
你這人挺偏激的
As you say
照你這麼說
In Korea, as long as you get blessings from others, you can have an ordinary love in the eyes of others.
在韓國只要得到別人的祝福 談著別人眼中的平凡戀愛
Will they never break up?
就絕對不會分手嗎？
If we break up because of other people
如果會因為其他人而分手
That love was doomed to fail from the beginning
那段愛情一開始就注定失敗
If not, it means that the breakup was just because we no longer loved each other.
倘若不是的話 那就代表分手只是因為不愛了
I've already confessed to you
我已經跟你告白了
But my desire to date you has not changed. Please think about it carefully.
而我想跟你交往的心意依舊沒變 你好好考慮一下吧
I think the problem is not with me, but with you
我認為問題不在我，是出在你身上
Look at the way you are pretending to be awesome
瞧你那副故作厲害的樣子
I am already very powerful, don’t you know?
我本來就很厲害，你不知道嗎？
That really makes you want to curse, right?
那真的讓人想罵髒話，對吧？
Damn it makes me want to curse
真他媽讓我想罵人
Calm down, don't get excited
冷靜點，別激動
He said I was incompetent
他說我無能
I really don’t understand which period drama Se Yong is acting in
我真的不明白世容 在演哪個時期的時代劇
Alas, Seyong is essentially a pharmaceutical company.
唉唷，世容的本質是製藥公司嘛
that kind of place
那種地方
somewhat conservative
多少有點保守
They don't even have any common sense
他們連一點常識都沒有
Because the standards are different
因為標準不同嘛
Hey, how can there be any so-called standards for common sense?
喂，常識哪有所謂的標準可言？
What the public thinks is right is common sense
大眾認為正確的事就是常識
If everyone has their own standards, how can it be called common sense?
要是人人都有各自的標準 怎麼稱得上是常識？
Have worked in the company for a long time
在公司工作久了
People's standards may be shaken
人的標準可能會有所動搖
Otherwise, why would anyone be willing to accept the mistakes made by company representatives?
不然大家為什麼會願意 攬下公司代表犯的錯
Are you still sacrificing your life for the company?
還為公司捨身賣命呢？
Not at all
才不是呢
That's because they are afraid
那是因為他們害怕
The life I have devoted my whole life to is worthless.
奉獻了一輩子的人生就此一文不值
Only then will your own value change...
才會改變自身的價值…
I really don’t understand that kind of person, my God!
我真的搞不懂那種人了，天啊！
I heard what you said
聽了你說的話
Suddenly reminds me of a certain bastard from before
突然讓我想起以前某個混蛋
Which bastard?
哪個混蛋？
When I was an agent
我以前還是代理時
Reported a supervisor’s wrongdoing to the Inspection Team
曾向監察組舉發某位上司的不法行為
But some bastard who knows that better than anyone else
但某個比誰都還清楚那件事的混蛋
But when questioned by the inspection team, he denied it completely
卻在監察組問話時全盤否認
Choose to protect your boss
選擇包庇自己的上司
This is too ridiculous
這也太荒謬了吧
So I was labeled an insider whistleblower.
於是我就被貼上內部告發者的標籤
After that, everyone obviously avoided me
在那之後，所有人都明擺著 對我避而遠之
I was not admitted through open recruitment in the first place.
我本來就不是公開招聘錄取的
But he was a journalist and was specially hired.
而是記者出身，被特別錄用
Now I'm even more annoying
這下我變得更加惹人厭
Even promotion has become out of reach
連升遷也變得遙不可及
so i left
所以我就離開了
I'm talking about Se Rong
我說的是世容
Shi Rong?
世容？
Yes, Se Yong
對啊，世容
Oh my God! So fed up
天啊！真是受夠了
drink
喝吧
But Yi Jung
不過伊貞
Don't give up
你別放棄
Why?
為什麼？
Although you may not be able to change anything on your own
雖然憑你一己之力可能改變不了什麼
But if you don't care about me
但如果連你都撒手不管
There's no chance to change again
就再也沒機會改變了
(Representative, Xu Dongxun)
（代表，徐東訓）
-Do you want to go there now? -Yes, senior
-你現在要過去嗎？ -對，前輩
I heard that you prepared those all by yourself.
聽說那些都是你一個人準備的
You should let others share the burden.
你應該讓其他人一起分擔啊
Because it concerns Se-yong
因為這關係到世容
Everyone is running for Ang's bakery
大家都為了昂的麵包店在奔波
I should do this
這點事應該由我來做
After all, Shirong is also our client.
世容畢竟也是我們的客戶
we have no choice
我們別無選擇
But you can’t ask them for money, right?
但這個無法向他們請款，對吧？
right
對
They should hope that we can give away online monitoring services
他們應該會希望 我們能贈送線上監控服務
I think so
我想也是
Anyway, thank you for your hard work
總之，辛苦你了
- No - That’s right
-不會 -也是啦
It's a representative's job to deal with this kind of thing, right?
處理這種事就是代表的職責，對吧？
That's right
沒錯
oh
喔
good
好
I heard that Representative Xu worked very hard on this matter.
聽說徐代表為了這件事很費心勞力
so what?
所以呢？
He came here for online monitoring of protein powder.
他是為了蛋白粉的線上監控而來的
It is required by the directors
是具理事要求的
that?
那個啊？
In short, the responsible unit is Global Communications, I believe you will do a good job.
總之，負責單位是環球傳播 想必你們會做得很好
No, you must behave well
不對，是一定要好好表現
Shirong is not a company that is easy to bully
世容可不是間好欺負的公司
How easy is it to make other people's money?
想賺別人的錢談何容易啊？
Isn't it?
不是嗎？
Yes, you are right
是，你說得對
At least Director Chen still wants to talk to you in person.
至少陳室長還是想找你親自聊聊的
Yes, thank you for taking such good care of me
是，謝謝他這麼關照我
The situation is not optimistic, right?
情況很不樂觀吧？
right
對
In addition to Representative Lin’s personal account
除了林代表的個人帳號
And all social media comment areas managed by Shi Yong
還有世容管理的所有社群媒體留言區
It's best to close them all temporarily
最好都暫時關閉起來
I checked on the way here
我在來的路上確認過
The Internet is now filled with calls for crusade
網路上現在充斥著討伐聲浪
OK
好的
Yes, thank you for confirming it for us
是，謝謝你幫我們確認
Okay, I'll take my leave then
好，那我告辭了
Wait, that...
等等，那個…
I heard your clients are also involved.
聽說你們的客戶也牽連其中
I didn't expect you to take care of this personally.
我沒想到你會親自關照這件事
On the one hand, I also think our request is too unreasonable.
一方面我也覺得 我們的要求過於無理了
as i just said
正如我剛才所說
Global Communications is a partner of Serong
環球傳播是世容的協力廠商
All we do is try our best to meet customer requirements
我們所做的只是盡力滿足客戶的要求
Please remember this
請你務必記得這點
Okay, I'll keep it in mind
好，我會銘記在心的
OK, bye
好，再見
take care
請慢走
He also gave me the ingredients test report from the Food and Drug Administration.
食藥處的成分檢驗報告也是他給我的
You have nothing to do with this?
你和這件事毫無關聯嗎？
What did you say?
你說什麼？
If you didn't hear it, let me ask again
你如果沒聽到，那我再問一次
Team leader
組長
You and this protein powder incident
你和這次的蛋白粉事件
No connection at all?
毫無關聯嗎？
Agent Guo, if you know anything, just tell me.
郭代理，你知道什麼就告訴我嘛
Senior, I really don’t know anything.
前輩，我真的什麼都不知道
How could you, the ace of the sales team, know nothing?
你是營業組的王牌 怎麼可能一無所知？
-Senior -huh?
-前輩 -嗯？
I really don't know anything
我真的什麼都不知道
That was all done by Team Leader Zhao alone.
那都是趙組長一個人進行的
I go first
我先走了
Agent Guo
郭代理
Team Leader Zhao has the sole authority to handle the upgrade of the protein powder formula this time.
這次蛋白粉配方升級的事 由趙組長全權處理
So the other groups don’t know anything about it.
所以其他組一概不知情
This is the ingredient analysis information you requested
這是你要求的成分分析資料
Only this?
就這些嗎？
right
對
research group to date
研究組至今
I still have the ingredient analysis table previously issued by Dongxin.
還保留著東新之前出具的成分分析表
(Equipment warehouse)
（備品倉庫）
Yes, there are limits to what we can do
沒錯，我們能做的有限
Do you want
要不要
Report directly to the inspection team?
直接向監察組舉發？
Do you want everyone to quit?
你想讓大家都離職嗎？
Then the public relations office will really collapse.
那樣公關室真的會瓦解
Houji should be able to survive.
厚佶應該能存活下來吧
That brat said he didn't want to have anything to do with it
那個臭小子說他不想管這件事
I will survive too
我也會活下來的
Otherwise, who will make the money for milk powder?
不然誰來賺奶粉錢？
So don’t even think about reporting it to the inspection team.
所以你別想跟監察組舉發
In this case
這樣的話
I'll tell you what's really the key
我告訴你們什麼才是真正的關鍵
Team Leader Song
宋組長
We need to investigate him further.
我們得深入調查他
Then do you want to meet the other team leaders?
那要不要去見見其他組長？
I'll go find Team Leader Chi
我去找池組長
Team leader pool?
池組長？
This is no longer a problem we can solve
這已經不是我們能解決的問題了
what i can do for you
我能為你做的
Just to help you reduce the punishment as much as possible
就是盡可能地幫你減輕懲戒
But I'm not sure now whether I can do it
但我現在也無法確定能否做到
Not to mention the other team members' affairs.
其他組員的事就更不用談了
besides
還有
Senior Song should also have his own reasons
宋前輩應該也有自己的理由
And I can't ignore that
而我不能忽視那點
Caimin agent
才旻代理
It seems wrong to do this
這樣做似乎是不對的
How can I…
我怎麼能…
How could I stab Team Leader Song in the back?
我怎麼能從背後捅宋組長一刀呢？
No, I'm not asking you to do this, Team Leader Cui
不，我不是要你這麼做，崔組長
i just hope you
我只是希望你
Can you help us thoroughly investigate the ins and outs of this matter?
能協助我們徹查這件事的來龍去脈
That's what it means to me
那對我來說就是那個意思
You want to investigate deeply everything related to Team Leader Song?
你們想深入調查與宋組長有關的一切
me
我這個人
The reason why I can still stay in this company till now
之所以還能在這間公司撐到現在
It depends on loyalty
靠的就是義氣
I will never do anything that harms the organization or my colleagues
我絕不會做出危害組織或同僚的事
Maybe you will be disappointed after hearing this
也許你聽了會感到失望
But that's who I am
但我就是那樣的人
Just pretend that what we met today never happened.
今天見面的事就當沒發生過吧
Take care of yourself
你多保重身體
I'll pay the bill
我來買單
Let’s go find Director Goo
我們去找具理事吧
She has the right to investigate this matter and I believe she will do the same.
她有權調查這件事 我相信她也會這麼做的
But there is so little evidence
但證據實在太少了
The only evidence we have is the ingredient analysis table
我們握有的證據 就只有那份成分分析表而已
Besides, her current situation is not very good either.
再說她現在的處境也不太好
I know everything
我都知道
But she's our last resort
但她是我們最後能求助的對象了
It also takes courage to ask a good boss for help
向一個好上司尋求幫助也需要勇氣
About the Victims of the Protein Powder Incident
關於蛋白粉事件的受害者
What does the sales team think?
營業組是怎麼想的？
Yes, because this incident is not simple
是，因為這起事件不單純
Therefore, the sales team also attaches great importance to this matter and decided to recall all products
所以營業組也很看重這件事 並決定召回所有產品
good
好
In addition, reporter Choi Huiying of Daguo Ilbo
另外，《大國日報》的崔慧瑛記者
The ingredient analysis table she presented...
她所出示的成分分析表…
but
不過
The analysis form provided to us by the Food and Drug Administration shows that there is no problem
食藥處提供給我們的分析表 上頭顯示沒有問題
certainly
當然
Analysis results will vary depending on the sample analyzed.
分析結果會依據 分析樣品的不同而有差異
I guess that's why the company decided to recall all the products
我想那也是公司決定召回 所有產品的原因
So the samples are different?
所以樣品不同？
right
對
That, Director Goo
那個，具理事
According to Director Chen
據陳室長所言
The company has decided to take punishment
公司已經決定要做出懲戒
And punishing those two people is the biggest apology the company can express.
而懲戒那兩個人就是 公司所能表達的最大歉意了
Is Director Chen in the company now?
陳室長現在人在公司嗎？
He scheduled a vacation before the personnel committee convened.
他在人事委員會召開前都排了休假
The phone is also turned off
手機也關機了
What's the point of having a meeting with just a few of us ?
只有我們幾個聚在一起開會 有什麼意義呢？
This matter seems to have been decided...
這件事似乎已有定論…
okay, I get it
好，我知道了
You guys go out
你們出去吧
Director Goo seems to be helpless.
具理事似乎也無可奈何了
that's what i want to say
那正是我想說的
This is what I just wanted to say
我剛才想說的就是這個
Wait, you really have to watch the PR office.
等等，你們真的要眼睜睜看著公關室
Reduced to a state of fragmentation?
淪落到支離破碎的下場嗎？
What can we do? The PR office is the weakest department
我們哪有什麼辦法？ 公關室可是最弱的部門
Um
嗯
This is not something that a mere sales team leader can accomplish alone.
這不是區區一個營業組組長 能獨自完成的事
Unless someone high-level is helping him behind the scenes
除非有高層在背後幫他
right
對
And that ingredient analysis table...
還有那個成分分析表…
Team Leader Song Xuantai just reported this matter to me
剛才宋宣泰組長有向我報告這件事
He said because the samples were different
他說因為樣品不同
The ingredient analysis table provided by the Food and Drug Administration shows that Se Yong’s sample did not ask...
而食藥處提供的成分分析表 顯示世容的樣品沒有問…
No
不
The samples are the same
樣品是一樣的
The person who provided the analysis table was also team leader Song Xuantai
提供那份分析表的人也是宋宣泰組長
You said the samples are the same?
你說樣品是一樣的？
right
對
Director Gu
具理事
I didn't express my suspicions to save myself.
我不是為了救自己才說出我的懷疑
I don't think so either
我也不認為
What can be found out or resolved before convening the personnel committee ?
在召開人事委員會前 能查明什麼或解決什麼
if not?
不然呢？
The reason why I decided to tell you these things
我之所以決定向你說出這些事
Because of
是因為
I don't think you're going to ignore this like the rest of Seyong's senior management.
我認為你不會像其他世容高層一樣 對這件事置之不理
You won't give up just because you're in a disadvantaged position.
你也不會因為屈居弱勢就放棄
Even after the personnel committee ends
就算人事委員會結束後
I also hope you can find out about this
我也希望你能查明這件事
but after that
但在那之後
I might not be alive anymore
我說不定就不在世容了
In other words, if you want to launch an investigation
也就是說若想展開調查
We have to hurry up before the personnel committee convenes.
就得趕在人事委員會召開之前
so
所以說
It 's time for us to stop being silent and show them.
我們別再悶不吭聲 該讓他們見識一下了
As the saying goes, "A dog in a hurry will jump over the wall."
俗話說“狗急跳牆”
So what to do?
那要怎麼做？
-Will everyone resign together? -Don't do that
-大家一起辭職嗎？ -不要搞那套
Slogans like "We want to get to the bottom of things"
“我們希望徹底查明真相” 類似這種標語
How about uploading it to the company discussion forum?
上傳到公司討論區如何？
"Find out the truth thoroughly"?
“徹底查明真相”？
You are exaggerating too
你也太誇張了
Have you ever participated in a protest? Do you know what a petrol bomb is?
你有參加過抗議活動嗎？ 知道什麼是汽油彈嗎？
It seems you are quite experienced
看來你挺有經驗的
In fact, Agent Liu was also wrong, wasn't he?
其實柳代理也有錯，不是嗎？
I heard that reporter is his friend
聽說那個記者是他的朋友
This means that he has no self-awareness as a publicist
這代表他沒有身為公關的自覺
Also, the person mentioned in the forum post is Agent Park.
還有，討論區貼文 提及的當事人就是朴代理啊
In my opinion, those who do wrong should be punished
在我看來，對做錯事的人 處以懲戒是應該的
wrong
不對
it's not like that
不是那樣的
Agent Yoo did not leak any information.
柳代理才沒有洩漏情報
Besides, that's not the point.
再說那又不是重點
Something happened but you just want to cover it up, that's the real problem
出了事卻只想掩蓋 那才是真正的問題
As for Agent Park
至於朴代理
She's just a scapegoat
她只是個替死鬼
You don’t even know this and you dare to call yourself a public relations office employee?
你連這個都不知道 還敢自稱是公關室員工
Anyway, let’s wait until the disciplinary action comes out.
總之等懲戒處分出來再說吧
Maybe they'll get away with it.
說不定他們會逃過一劫
Then we will look like fools
到時候會顯得我們像笨蛋一樣
Don't gather everyone to talk about what you have and what you don't have.
不要聚集大家說些有的沒的
Where did Agent Park go?
朴代理去哪裡了？
She just said she was going to the hospital
她剛才說要去一趟醫院
Visit the proud bakery owner
探望那位昂的麵包店老闆
I went to see him too
我也去看過他了
Why are you going?
你為什麼要去？
Because I feel so sorry
因為我覺得過意不去
The thought of someone passing out from the amount of stress I'm under
一想到有人因為我 承受巨大的壓力而昏倒
My mood is very heavy
我的心情就很沉重
The current market response is gradually changing
目前市場的反應漸漸在改變
Ang’s bakery sales have also gradually picked up
昂的麵包店銷售額也逐漸回升了
Sorry, boss
對不起，老闆
it's all my fault
都是我的錯
You say you have no choice
你說你別無選擇
no
不是的
That's what everyone says to me
是每個人都那麼對我說
But I should fight to the death to stop them
但我應該要誓死阻止他們到底
If I can't do that, then I should leave that company.
假使做不到 那我就該離開那間公司才對
but
不過
Sorry I didn't do that
對不起我沒有那麼做
I'm also sorry that I delayed coming until now.
也很抱歉我拖到現在才來
to be honest
老實說
I'm scared
我很害怕
I'm afraid that Boss Huang might have something unexpected happen to him
我怕黃老闆會有個萬一
I'm also afraid that after we actually meet, you will all blame me.
也怕實際見到面之後，你們都責怪我
sorry
對不起
that…
那個…
If I have to say it, it’s Se Rong’s fault.
硬要說的話，是世容的錯才對
I still know this
這點我還是知道的
But look
不過你看
You are the only one who apologizes
道歉的只有你
How long has it been since I uploaded that post? Saeyong hasn’t even made an official statement.
我上傳那篇貼文都過多久了 世容連個正式聲明都沒有
sorry
對不起
This is all I can say now
我現在能說的只有這句話了
(Se Yong)
（世容）
If this continues, we will all be fired, right?
這樣下去，我們都會被解僱吧？
Then take the legal route
那就走法律途徑啊
correct
對了
Your mother is a judge, right?
你媽是法官吧？
Why are you saying this suddenly?
怎麼突然說這個？
Then she must know many relevant people in the legal field
那她一定認識很多法律界的相關人士
At least it will be beneficial to us in the lawsuit
至少打官司時會對我們有利
My mother should know a lot of people
我媽應該認識很多人
but I do not have
但我沒有
Yes, you have a bad relationship with your mother
對喔，你跟你媽關係不好
Yes, we don’t have a good relationship, and we haven’t seen each other for a long time.
對，我們關係不好，也很久沒見了
Every time your mother is mentioned, you lose your temper
每次提到你媽，你就發脾氣
how about you?
那你呢？
You still refuse to call her mother
你到現在還不肯叫她媽媽
My situation is different from yours
我的情況跟你又不一樣
Don't compare you to me
別拿你跟我相提並論
Yeah, your situation is worse than mine, bleak and miserable.
是啊，你的情況比我還要 糟糕、淒涼又悲慘
-Are you satisfied? -When you said that, I felt worse again.
-滿意了嗎？ -被你這麼一說，心情又更糟了
It's time to prepare
該準備了
Are you relaxing now?
現在放鬆一點了嗎？
Absolutely not
完全沒有
Before convening the personnel committee of Deputy Yoo Jae-min and Deputy Park Yoon-so
在召開柳才旻代理 及朴允昭代理的人事委員會之前
There's something I need to confirm first
有件事得先確認一下
It’s about the launch process of protein powder products with upgraded formulas
是關於配方升級版的 蛋白粉產品上市過程
What does that have to do with the case being heard by the Personnel Committee today ?
那跟今天人事委員會的審理案件 有什麼關係？
Manufacturers supplying protein powder raw materials have made changes
供應蛋白粉原料的廠商有異動
I think you all should know
我想你們應該都知道
Switched from Dongshin to PF
從東新換成了PF
And this new manufacturer
而這家新廠商
It's a company run by a relative of Zhao Zhenrui, the leader of the sales team.
是營業一組組長趙鎮瑞親戚開的公司
Whether it is factory facilities, manpower or R&D capabilities
不論是工廠設施、人力或研發能力
They are extremely backward in every aspect and are a messed up company.
他們在各方面都極度落後 是家亂七八糟的公司
Therefore, defective products are an expected result
因此產品不良是預料中的結果
Moreover, when there are already victims
況且在已經出現受害者的情況下
They even teamed up with each other to cover it up
他們甚至相互聯手來掩蓋此事
What on earth are you talking about?
你到底在說些什麼？
-You like playing golf, right? -What?
-你喜歡打高爾夫球吧？ -什麼？
It's just a simple question
這只是個簡單的問題
Do you like to play golf?
你喜歡打高爾夫球嗎？
(One day before the personnel committee meeting)
（召開人事委員會一天前）
You are here, but why are you here?
你來啦，不過你怎麼會來這裡？
Can we have a chat?
我們可以聊一下嗎？
i have been thinking
我一直在思考
“ What is Team Leader Song Xuantai’s stance on this matter?
“宋宣泰組長對這件事 抱持什麼立場？
How deeply involved is he with Team Leader Zhao's corruption?
他跟趙組長貪汙一事牽連得有多深？
Does he have no idea, or is he just...
他是毫不知情，還是他就是…
The core figure in this corruption incident?
這次貪汙事件的核心人物？
If not, does he play the role of a ghost in this round? "
如果都不是，難道他在這一局 擔任鬼牌的角色嗎？”
All right
好吧
maybe you don't know
也許你並不知道
The ingredient analysis sheet that I handed over...
自己交出去的那份成分分析表…
is fake
是偽造的
If you just accept the analysis table given by Team Leader Zhao
假如你只是單純收下 趙組長給的分析表而已
Although Team Leader Zhao is from the same hometown as you,
雖然趙組長跟你同鄉
I'm also a junior from the same school as you.
也是跟你同所學校的後輩
But you may have nothing to do with Team Leader Zhao’s corruption.
但你跟趙組長貪汙一事 可能沒有任何關聯
right
對
I might think so
我說不定會那麼想
but
不過
This seems unjustifiable to anyone.
這任誰看來都說不過去
Especially someone like Se Yong
尤其是像世容這種
Relying on personal connections and alumni relationships to build bridges
專靠人脈及校友關係搭建橋梁
support each other
彼此互相支持
This is especially true for companies that provide help
並給予幫助的企業更是如此
Director Gu…
具理事…
It was Chief Chen and Chief Larkin who set up the trap.
是陳室長拉金本部長下水的
And you are the middleman who helps match up Director Chen and Team Leader Zhao, right?
而幫陳室長與趙組長牽線的 中間人就是你吧？
That's the heart of this protein powder scandal
那就是這次蛋白粉醜聞的核心
It is also the origin of all events
也是一切事件的起源
you hope to
你希望
What do I do?
我怎麼做？
Do you want me to be an inside whistleblower?
你要我去當內部告發者嗎？
I…
我…
I look down on that kind of person
我瞧不起那種人
Team Leader Song
宋組長
Don't sink with the boat under your feet
別跟著腳下的船一起沉沒
Let's switch to another ship as soon as possible
趁早換搭別艘船吧
Times have changed now
現在時代已經變了
It doesn't matter even if you do that
就算那麼做也無妨
"Agent Song Xuantai who helped Section Chief Chen Bingwan cover up the crime of accepting bribes"
“幫陳炳萬科長掩蓋 收受賄賂罪行的宋宣泰代理”
You have to break away from this relationship
你得跳脫這層關係
Stop letting your past life determine your worth
別再讓過去的世容決定你的價值
Let it be reflected in Seyong’s future
讓它體現在世容的未來吧
You will know after reading it, currently replacing Dongxin
你看了就會知道，目前取代東新
The raw materials are provided by PF Factory, a company run by a relative of team leader Zhao Zhenrui.
提供原料的是PF工廠 那是趙鎮瑞組長親戚開的公司
As far as I know, President Park Ji-hoon of PF will provide
據我所知，PF的朴志勳社長會提供
Golf membership coupons and cars are given to the head of the finance department and office manager Chen in return.
高爾夫球會員券及汽車 給金本部長和陳室長作為回報
Sorry for not informing you in advance
很抱歉沒能提前告知你
Chief Kim, do you have the membership coupon for Lucun CC?
金本部長，你手頭有 呂村CC的會員券吧？
Chief Chen has membership coupons for Eastern Benister
而陳室長則有東部貝尼斯特的會員券
Yeochon CC’s membership coupons are worth 1.8 billion won
呂村CC的會員券價值18億韓元
Dongbu Benister’s membership coupons are worth 980 million won
而東部貝尼斯特的會員券 價值9億8千萬韓元
Stop talking about irrelevant things!
別再說那些毫不相關的事了！
Drag that woman out
把那女的拖出去
The person who presented the membership coupon was none other than President Park Ji-hoon of raw material manufacturer PF.
贈送會員券的人正是 原料廠商PF的朴志勳社長
And he is also the brother-in-law of Zhao Zhenrui, the leader of the sales team.
而他同時也是營業一組組長 趙鎮瑞的姐夫
I said drag that woman out
我說把那女的拖出去
Take away that woman who is talking nonsense!
把那個正在胡說八道的女人帶走！
Drag that woman out quickly!
快把那女的拖出去！
Didn't you hear what I said?
你沒聽到我說的話嗎？
You like more than just golf
你喜歡的不只是高爾夫球
You also like cars and luxury resorts
你還喜歡汽車跟豪華度假村
-enough - cash of course
-夠了 -當然還有現金
Shut up!
給我住嘴！
vice president
副社長
I have dedicated my whole life to Shirong
我把這一生都奉獻給了世容
You should know very well
你應該很清楚才對
Don't you know?
你不是知道嗎？
I gave it my all!
我付出了我的一切！
Is it just me?
只有我嗎？
No
不
no
不行
Inspection team
監察組
-Please investigate this matter thoroughly -Yes
-請徹底調查此事 -是
Is there anything you two want to say?
你們兩個有什麼話想說嗎？
I don't
我沒有
I…
我…
I have never been ashamed of Shi Rong
從來不曾因為世容感到羞愧
But that’s not because Shirong is really acting magnanimously.
但那並非世容真的行事坦蕩
It's because I have no expectations for the company
而是因為我對公司沒有期待
But this colleague next to me
但我身旁的這位同事
During the implementation of this project
在這次專案推行的過程中
I really blamed myself countless times
真的自責了無數次
Blaming myself for not objecting more actively
責怪自己沒能更積極地反對
she is very remorseful
她很懊悔
See her like that
看到她那個樣子
i feel ashamed of myself
我為自己感到羞愧
I also realized that I have been doing nothing
也領悟到一直毫無作為的我
It is also part of the reason why Shirong culture is so outdated and unreasonable.
同時也是造成世容文化 如此過時又不合理的部分原因
So I plan to change starting with me
因此我打算從我開始改變
I decided to look forward to it
我決定懷抱期待
That's all I want to say
我想說的就是這些
you first
你先請
You told me the problem was
你曾告訴過我問題出在
Serong’s corporate culture, right?
世容的企業文化，對吧？
right
對
Can that change overnight?
那能在一夕之間改變嗎？
Although not that fast
雖然不會那麼快
But it seems to have begun to change
但似乎已經開始改變了
Yeah?
是嗎？
About internal culture improvement plan
關於內部文化改善計畫
you have to take responsibility
你要負起責任
Complete the plan well
好好完成計畫
yes
是
Thanks a lot
辛苦你了
You were so handsome just now
你剛才帥呆了
It's because you are handsome
是因為你很帥氣
all because of you
都是因為你
It's all thanks to you that I had that thought
我會產生那種想法都是多虧了你
Really, please take that line back
真是的，拜託收回那種臺詞
I'm getting goosebumps
我都起雞皮疙瘩了
By the way, that golf course membership ticket?
話說回來，那個高爾夫球場的會員券
How did Director Goo know?
具理事是怎麼知道的？
She even knows the price clearly
她連價格都一清二楚
There must be someone inside helping her
一定有內應在幫她
Could it be Team Leader Song?
該不會是宋組長吧？
impossible
不可能
not him
不是他
Could it be him?
難道是他嗎？
Didn't the vice president just order a thorough investigation?
副社長剛才不是下令 要徹底調查清楚了嗎？
If Team Leader Song does something wrong, he will definitely be found out.
倘若宋組長有做錯事 一定會被查出來的
Yes, you are right
沒錯，你說得對
You should have a drink today
今天得喝一杯吧
I have an appointment
我有約了
Are you planning to officially start a relationship?
你們打算要正式交往了嗎？
Yes, probably
對，應該吧
Do you like…
你喜歡…
That person?
那個人嗎？
right
對
I like him, he is a good man
我喜歡他，他是個好人
That's enough
這樣就足夠了
You ask me how to tell whether it is friendship or love?
你問我要怎麼分辨是友情的喜歡 還是愛情的喜歡？
Because even if you are a friend , you might like her very much.
因為就算是朋友 也可能喜歡得不得了啊
Aren't you confused with love?
難道你不會跟愛情的喜歡搞混嗎？
Are you stupid? How could there be confusion?
你是笨蛋嗎？怎麼可能會搞混？
is that so?
是這樣嗎？
Otherwise, try to think about whether you would want to kiss or sleep with her.
不然你試著想想 你會不會想跟她接吻或上床
Let’s see if you can do it or not
看你究竟做不做得到
Then there's the answer
那樣就有答案了
What's wrong? who is it?
怎麼了？是誰？
Among the friends you know...
你所認識的朋友當中…
No way?
不會吧？
What?
什麼？
Could it be...
該不會是…
Reporter Choi, right?
崔記者吧？
Damn, things get complicated.
該死，事情變複雜了
you…
你…
Huiying confessed to you
慧瑛向你告白了啊
-What? -She's exactly your type, right?
-什麼？ -她完全是你喜歡的型，對吧？
Hey, get out of here after drinking the wine
喂，酒喝完就快滾
I really can't stand you
真受不了你
If not Reporter Choi, then who?
如果不是崔記者，那是誰？
Actually it is...
其實就是…
you
你
Neuropathy
神經病
you crazy
你這瘋子
Is it Yun Zhao?
是允昭吧？
The meat is super soft and almost melts in your mouth
肉質超柔軟的，簡直入口即化
Not to that point yet
還不到那種地步吧
Don't pick on my bad language, I'm just saying the meat is delicious
別挑我語病，我是在說肉好吃
good
好
This meal is mine
這頓算我的
Representative, enjoy it.
代表，你好好享用吧
I treat you because I want to thank you
我是因為感謝你才請客的
But can you please stop calling me representative?
不過你能不能別叫我代表了？
This title is too standard
這個稱呼太制式了
How about calling you "honey"?
那叫你“親愛的”怎麼樣？
I'm just kidding
我開玩笑的
It's too exaggerated to call it that.
那樣叫太誇張了
What about "baby"?
那麼“寶貝”呢？
What?
什麼？
How can we call you that when we have no relationship ?
我們又沒有交往 怎麼能那樣稱呼你呢？
Didn't we have a relationship?
我們沒有交往嗎？
Have we dated?
我們交往了嗎？
When did it start?
從什麼時候開始的？
Then let’s start dating from today. Today is the first day.
那就從今天開始交往吧 今天是第一天
Isn't it time yet?
還不是時候嗎？
Do you need a little more time?
你需要再一點時間嗎？
But I can't seem to wait any longer
但我好像等不下去了
Am I being a bit selfish?
我是不是有點自私？
Is that your answer?
那就是你的答案嗎？
This answer is a bit unsettling
這回答讓人有點不安
Does this mean I need to have a good cry when I get home?
這表示我回到家需要大哭一場嗎？
So
那麼
Today is the first day of our relationship
今天就是我們交往的第一天
Are you negotiating?
你這是在協商嗎？
You can also refuse
你也可以拒絕
All right
好吧
After all, it feels like I like you more
畢竟感覺是我喜歡你多一點
make a deal
成交
- over there - okay
-在那邊 -好
(American Chinatown snacks)
（美國唐人街小吃）
-Right? -right
-對吧？ -對
That’s right…
沒錯…
- they were a little panicked - um
-他們當時有點驚慌 -嗯
You want me to apologize publicly?
要我公開道歉？
right
對
You must bend down and apologize in person
你一定要親自彎腰道歉
In Korea, you may lose your job because of a hidden ad
在韓國，可能會因為 一個隱藏廣告就丟了飯碗
But we are using social media to spread false news in South Korea
而我們卻在韓國 利用社群媒體散布虛假消息
Therefore we need a sincere apology from the company representative
因此我們需要公司代表的真誠道歉
no problem
沒問題
correct
對了
You also have to talk about the internal cons
你也必須談談內部弊端
Do we need to expose our company's scandals to the public one by one?
我們有必要把公司的醜聞 一一攤在大眾面前嗎？
You can't just apologize
你不能只是嘴上道歉
You must also demonstrate your responsible attitude as a representative
還要展現身為一個代表 勇於負責的態度
So we can't hide anything anymore
所以我們不能再隱瞞任何事情
Then let's make a public apology.
那就來場公開道歉吧
I was busy dealing with the Human Resources Committee, so the response was slow.
我忙著處理人事委員會的事 導致對應得比較慢
I'm sorry about that
這點我感到很抱歉
I knew I chose the golden axe
我就知道我選的是金斧頭
instead of a bad ax
而不是把爛斧頭
us
我們
I sincerely apologize to you
真心地向你道歉
We will definitely try our best
我們一定會盡最大努力
Don't let this happen again
不再讓這種事情發生
Shi Yong Hui strives to become a company that fulfills corporate social responsibilities
世容會努力成為 履行企業社會責任的公司
We apologize again
我們再次致上歉意
I am Se Rong’s representative, Lin Zhixian
我是世容的代表，林知賢
first
首先
Regarding the recent controversy caused by our company’s protein powder products
針對最近我們公司 蛋白粉產品造成的爭議
caused concern among the people
引起了國民的憂慮
I would like to express my deepest apologies for this
我要為此致上最深的歉意
We are conducting thorough internal monitoring
我們正透過徹底的內部監察
Try to find out the exact cause so you can take follow-up measures
努力找出確切的原因 以採取後續處置措施
Based on the results of internal monitoring
根據內部監察的結果
We found that within the company
我們發現公司內部
Major problems occurred during the communication process
溝通過程中出現了重大問題
we have not reflected
我們未經反省
A routine of repeating past mistakes
反覆犯下過往錯誤的慣例
I think this kind of thing should never happen
我認為這種事情絕對不該發生
In addition, for the failure to thoroughly confirm in advance
此外，針對事前未能徹底確認
Product safety lapses
產品安全性的疏失
Even if it’s just once…
哪怕僅有一次…
I went to see her
我去見過她了
No forgiveness either
也不容寬恕
The woman in the picture just now
剛剛畫面中那個女人
To prevent similar incidents from happening again
為防止類似事件再次發生
We will significantly improve the way we communicate with the outside world
我們將大幅改善與外界的溝通方式
- Sit down for a moment - Shi Rong played a good chess game
-你坐一下 -下了一手好棋的世容
Can it be reversed?
究竟能否逆轉
The current public opinion of the people is lukewarm, attracting public attention
目前國民冷淡的輿論，備受大眾關注
So what do you want to do?
所以你想怎麼做？
I shouldn't have gone to see her
我不該去見她的
After meeting her, I realized that even though I hate her
見過她之後，我發現儘管我很討厭她
But I also miss her very much
卻也很想念她
I feel a little sorry for you
我覺得有點對不起你
Why do you feel sorry for me?
為什麼覺得對不起我？
Aren't you still angry with her?
你不也還在生她的氣嗎？
Because she left us and walked away
因為她拋下我們一走了之
I know exactly how you feel
我很清楚你是怎樣的心情
so
所以
When I start to miss her a little
當我開始有點想她時
will feel guilty
就會感到愧疚
I didn't mean to hide it from you
我不是故意要瞞你的
It's just that I don't feel comfortable lying all the time.
只是不停地撒謊讓我覺得不太自在
Yu Zhen
俞真
First of all, I appreciate you telling me honestly
首先，我很感謝你誠實地告訴我
What do you think of your mother?
你對媽媽的想法
But I hope you don't feel guilty about me
但我希望你不要對我感到愧疚
Whatever feelings you have for her, that's up to you.
不管你對她抱有怎樣的情感 那都取決於你
And I will respect you
而我都會給予尊重
thanks for saying that
謝謝你這麼說
Then I'll go back to the room
那我回房間了
I can do it too…
我也會…
Trying to see
努力看看的
Although not sure what the outcome will be
雖然不確定結果會如何
Why are you looking for me?
你怎麼會找我？
Is there a problem?
有什麼事嗎？
Have you heard about me?
你聽說我的事了嗎？
What's up?
什麼事？
I'm getting ready to run for mayor.
我正準備參選市長
But I have to win the party primary first
但我得先贏得黨內初選
It turned out to be this
原來是這件事
Why don't you help me?
你何不幫幫我呢？
What are you doing? Do you want to ask me for help now or what?
搞什麼？你現在是想 拜託我還是怎樣？
This is not a request, but a proposal
這不是拜託，而是提議
Many people recommend you to me
很多人都向我推薦你
And I can't completely ignore it
而我又不能完全忽視
I see
原來如此
I reject your proposal
我拒絕你的提議
I'm not happy at all
我一點都不樂意
Yeah?
是嗎？
I originally wanted to see your ability
我本來想見識你的能力
Anyway, I gave you another chance
總之，我給過你另一次機會了
You are the one who is dismissive
不屑一顧的人是你
This conclusion really fits your style
這結論還真符合你的作風
Okay, I think we're done talking, so I'll leave first.
好，我想談得差不多了，那我先走了
Thank you for taking the time to stop by
謝謝你抽空過來
that's all?
就這樣？
It seems you have other expectations
看來你還抱有其他期待
Is it about Yu Zhen?
是關於俞真的事嗎？
What a shame, I have nothing to say
真遺憾，我沒什麼要說的
It seems you guessed wrong
看來你猜錯了
If I'm not mistaken, I won't come at all
要是沒猜錯，我根本不會來
(Ahn Eun-seok)
（安恩錫）
(Cheongdam cram school)
（清潭補習班）
(Se Yong)
（世容）
Speaking of Team Leader Song
說到宋組長
It is said that he helped cover up all of Team Leader Zhao’s illegal activities.
據說趙組長所有的不法行為 都是他幫忙掩蓋的
In exchange for a death-free gold medal
藉以換取免死金牌
Think about it, his child is in Australia
你想想，他的孩子在澳洲啊
Then he must have gained something from Team Leader Zhao , right?
那他一定有從趙組長那邊 撈到什麼好處，對吧？
-Maybe not. -I was shocked.
-說不定沒有啊 -嚇我一跳
Why do you show up silently every time?
你怎麼每次都無聲無息地冒出來？
I think Team Leader Song
我認為宋組長
Maybe not that kind of person
也許不是那種人
Are you crazy? Why speak for him?
你瘋了嗎？幹嘛幫他說話？
no
不是啊
I just feel that way
我只是有那種感覺
You just…
你只要…
Just think about yourself
為自己著想就好
No one will help you at all
根本不會有人幫你
so
所以
Just protect yourself
保護你自己就好
Maybe he was acting so strong to protect himself
也許他是為了保護自己 才會表現得那麼強勢
Do you have a high fever?
你發高燒了嗎？
-Brother -Hmm
-哥 -嗯
Her brain is burned out and she's talking nonsense
她腦子燒壞了，在胡言亂語
Then she needs to be hospitalized
那得讓她住院才行
Is it 119?
是119嗎？
There's a guy here who's talking crazy nonsense
這裡有個瘋狂胡說八道的人
wait a minute
等等喔
My body temperature is even higher
我的體溫反而更高呢
Because I'm angry
因為我怒火中燒
Please actively participate in the internal culture improvement plan survey
請大家踴躍參與 內部文化改善計畫的問卷調查
Thanks
謝謝
Only your attention can change the world
唯有你們的關注才能改變世容
If you have anything you don’t understand or have other questions, you can ask me.
有不懂的地方或其他問題都可以問我
You can also fill out the questionnaire online
也能線上填寫問卷喔
(Please participate in the Internal Culture Improvement Plan Survey!)
（請參與內部文化 改善計畫問卷調查！）
(1. Evaluation system)
（一，評鑑制度）
(Seyong Internal Culture Improvement Plan Questionnaire)
（世容內部文化改善計畫問卷）
( How important do you think it is to set key performance indicators?)
（您認為設定 關鍵績效指標有多重要？）
(2. Internal company culture)
（二，公司內部文化）
(Results of internal culture improvement questionnaire)
（內部文化改善問卷調查結果）
(How satisfied are you with the culture within your company currently ?)
（您目前對於公司內部文化 有多滿意？）
( How important do you think it is to set key performance indicators?)
（您認為設定 關鍵績效指標有多重要？）
(Do you think you can communicate effectively with the team leader?)
（您認為能跟組長 有效進行溝通嗎？）
(can communicate effectively, can communicate well, cannot communicate)
（能有效溝通，能溝通 尚可，無法溝通）
Come on, Yun Zhao
來，允昭
Then Seung Hee...
那勝熙就…
in my opinion…
在我看來…
this…
這個…
The next item is
下一項是
Fair evaluation based on work results
依據工作成果的公正評鑑
The method is to select the score that suits the individual from one point to ten points.
進行方式是從一分到十分 選擇符合個人的分數
This is a list of systems they hope to introduce in the future
這份清單列出了 他們希望往後能引進的制度
This is much better than I expected
這比我預期的好太多了
Thanks a lot
辛苦你了
-Dinner together!
-聚餐！
-No problem, let's go
-沒問題，走吧
Hello, Team Leader Liu
喂，柳組長
Are you here to visit, you brat? He actually sat there and didn't help.
你這臭小子是來參觀的嗎？ 居然坐著不幫忙
Agent Park is left busy all by himself.
讓朴代理一個人忙得團團轉
what happened again? That girl is better than me
又怎麼了？那丫頭比我還厲害啊
"That girl"?
“那丫頭”？
what? Is this place filled with pink bubbles too?
什麼啊？這裡也充滿了粉紅泡泡嗎？
Sure enough, it’s better to be single, you can have ambiguities everywhere
果然還是單身好，到處都能搞曖昧
Everyone, I have a boyfriend, okay?
各位，我有男朋友好嗎？
Now it's time to reveal
現在是該揭曉的時候了
Liu Caimin was my classmate in elementary school and junior high school.
柳才旻是我的小學跟國中同學
OK, I'll say it again
好，我再說一次
This girl is better than me
這丫頭比我還要厲害
What's there to hide?
這有什麼好隱瞞的？
scared me
嚇我一跳
If you completely fooled us, then it's obviously no big deal.
你們徹底騙倒了我們 那明明就沒什麼大不了的
Then help arrange things quickly. Director Gu will be here soon.
那就快幫忙把東西擺好 具理事馬上就到了
OK, I'll help set it up
好，我來幫忙擺
By the way, I heard that both Chief Kim and Chief Chen have resigned.
對了，聽說金本部長 跟陳室長都提離職了
They mentioned it before the inspection results came out.
他們是在監察結果出來之前提的
What about Team Leader Song?
那宋組長呢？
He seems to have been under surveillance together , but I don’t know what the outcome will be.
他好像是一起接受監察的 但不知道結果如何
I'm really curious
我真的很好奇
What role did he play?
他究竟扮演了什麼角色？
Team leader Zhao also resigned, right?
趙組長也辭職了吧？
How could it be just him?
怎麼可能只有他？
Those who knew the truth about the victimization in advance but remained silent
那些事前知曉受害真相卻保持沉默
Also assisted the person responsible for falsifying information
還協助偽造資料的負責人
They were all fired one by one.
都一一被開除了
correct
對了
Were all the people in charge of the protein powder case in the public relations office having their salaries cut?
公關室負責蛋白粉案的相關人員 全都被減薪了吧？
After all, we made a mistake and we have to accept it calmly.
畢竟我們做錯了，得坦然接受才對
Director Goo is here!
具理事來了！
-Director Goo!
-具理事！
-welcome!
-歡迎！
-The presentation is beautiful. -Welcome
-擺盤真美 -歡迎
Celebrate with champagne
慶祝就是要喝香檳
Why do you carry so many bottles?
你怎麼帶這麼多瓶？
-How many bottles are there in total? -How many bottles did you bring?
-總共有幾瓶啊？ -你到底帶了幾瓶啊？
Thanks
謝謝
-Thank you, Director Goo -Thank you
-謝謝具理事 -謝謝
-Thank you for your hard work, everyone .
-大家都辛苦了 -謝謝你
Thanks
謝謝
-cheers!
-乾杯！
Thanks for your hard work!
辛苦了！
-Thank you for your hard work . -Thank you for your hard work.
-辛苦了 -大家辛苦了
- Well done. - Good job.
-幹得好 -辛苦了
-It's so delicious. -How does it taste?
-也太好吃了吧 -味道如何？
Very delicious
很好吃耶
That, Director Goo
那個，具理事
Maybe you feel a little panicked
也許你會感到有點驚慌
But I really have something to tell you
但我真的有話想跟你說
What is it?
是什麼？
I think
我想
become someone like you
成為像你一樣的人
If it's not too late
如果還不算太遲的話
That won't work
那樣可不行
I think so
我想也是
Yes, that's right, I was overestimating my abilities.
對，沒錯，我太不自量力了
you have to be a better person
你得成為更好的人
a better person than me
一個比我更優秀的人
What a great day today
今天真棒
I'm really your fan
我真的是你的粉絲
If you don't mind, could you sign it for me?
如果你不介意，能不能幫我簽個名？
-sign? -right
-簽名？ -對
What? Are you kidding me?
什麼？你是開玩笑的吧？
No, I'm 100% serious
不，我是百分之百認真的
Oh my god
天啊
Oh my God, how did you get this photo?
天啊，你怎麼拿到這張照片的？
OMG
我的天啊
"To Yun Zhao"
“致允昭”
Thank you
謝謝你
Oh my god
天啊
(Outline of Organizational Adjustment Case)
（組織調整案概要）
(Communications Department, Organizational Adjustment Case)
（傳播部門，組織調整案）
Are you sure the vice president will really agree to this?
你確定副社長真的會同意這個嗎？
He has no reason to stop
他沒有理由能阻止
Forget it, vice president
副社長就算了
What about Zheng Shouhuan?
那鄭首煥呢？
Oh my god
天啊
This is really innovative...
這實在是太創新…
At least be the head of the sales department
至少當營業本部長
Isn't it more suitable for you than the head of the Strategy Headquarters?
比策略本部長更適合你吧？
(Outline of Organizational Adjustment Case)
（組織調整案概要）
(Public Relations Group, Team Leader, Cui Yonghao)
（公關一組，組長，崔永皓）
Who put this?
這是誰放的？
(Application form for early retirement)
（提前退休申請書）
(I plan to apply for voluntary retirement due to company business reasons, please approve)
（本人因公司經營事由 打算申請自願退休，煩請批准）
(Announcement, 2023 organizational adjustment plan)
（公告，2023年度組織調整案）
(Communications Department, Head of Department Goo Yi-jung)
（傳播部門，具伊貞部門長）
(Business Department, Department Chief Zheng Qiurong)
（事業部門，鄭求榮部門長）
Alas, I saved you, these brats
唉唷，是我救了你們，這群臭小子
Especially the one over there , he really needs to be grateful to me.
尤其是那邊那個 他真的要好好感激我才對
Hey, what's going on? Please explain
喂，這是怎麼回事？你解釋一下
The company has established a new communications department
公司新設了一個傳播部門
There is a communications department and a strategy department underneath.
底下有傳播本部跟策略本部
The head of the communications department is Director Goo?
傳播部門長是具理事呢
Hey, the PR team and the marketing team have merged.
喂，公關組跟行銷組合併了
Several employees from the Strategy Office and Human Resources Office were also transferred here.
也有幾位策略室 跟人資室的員工被調過來
(2023 Serong Human Resources Appointment, Staff)
（2023年度世容人事任命，職員）
(Personnel appointment)
（人事任命）
Hello, I'm in the communications department's group
喂，我在傳播本部一組
oh? Me too
喔？我也是
(Ryu Jae-min, one group of broadcasters and Park Yun-soo, one group of broadcasters)
（柳才旻，傳播一組 朴允昭，傳播一組）
(Kim Houji, Lee Seung-hee)
（金厚佶，李勝熙）
(Communication Group 3, Agent)
（傳播三組，代理）
The pool leader is a group leader
池組長是一組組長
The leader of the second group is the leader of the marketing group. As for the leader of the third group
二組組長是行銷組組長 至於三組組長
It seems to be hired from outside, and it’s an unknown name.
看來是外聘的，是個不認識的名字
Section Chief Meng is also in the same group.
孟科長也是一組的呢
We are in the same group
我們同一組
Hello
喂
Agent Liu, you have been promoted to section chief.
柳代理，你升上科長了呢
congratulations
恭喜你
Hey, it’s true. Congratulations.
喂，真的耶，恭喜你
Oh my gosh, Seung Hee, you’ve been promoted to agent too
天啊，勝熙，你也升上代理了
yes!
是啊！
(SeRong HR appoints senior managers in 2023)
（2023年度世容人事任命 高階主管）
Team Leader Song…
宋組長…
(Song Xuantai, Head of Department)
（宋宣泰，本部長）
He was promoted to executive
他升上了常務
He also became the head of the communications department
還成為傳播本部的本部長
Senior, congratulations
前輩，恭喜你
Song Changzhu
宋常務
-Congratulations -Thank you
-恭喜你 -謝謝
Congratulations so much
太恭喜你了
- Seung Hee, congratulations. - Congratulations.
-勝熙，恭喜你 -恭喜
-Congratulations. -Thank you so much.
-太謝謝你了
-I will be loyal to you for the rest of my life -Hey
-我會一輩子效忠於你的 -喂
Congratulations on your promotion. You are now Section Chief Liu.
恭喜你升遷，你現在是柳科長了
It's so embarrassing. What kind of section chief do you call me?
真令人害臊，叫什麼科長啊？
-What should I call you from now on? -Wait me a moment
-我以後要怎麼稱呼你？ -等我一下
-As you like -Hello?
-隨你開心 -喂？
How about calling you the executive?
那就稱呼你常務如何？
Oh my god
天啊
congratulations
恭喜你
-Why are you all gathering here? - I will give you more advice in the future.
-你們幹嘛都聚過來啊？ -以後要多多指教了
Okay, got it, thank you
好啦，知道了，謝謝
-Hi -congratulations
-喂 -恭喜你
Jihyo, why did you come all the way?
智孝，你還特地跑來啊？
congratulations!
恭喜你！
Thanks
謝謝
-Please give me some advice -Okay
-請多多指教了 -好
Go back, that's enough
回去啦，夠了
Oh, it's true
唉唷，真是的
I'm going crazy
我要瘋了
Let's go eat something delicious
去吃點好吃的吧
-Okay, no problem . -Really?
-好，沒問題 -真的嗎？
Subtitle translation: Chen Yiying
字幕翻譯：陳怡穎